Register of the Richard Michael Fraser, Baron Fraser of Kilmorack Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Richard Michael Fraser, Baron Fraser of Kilmorack papers
1930-1977
98012
Hoover Institution Archives
97 manuscript boxes (40.5 linear feet)
Correspondence, minutes, memoranda, speeches, reports, and printed matter, relating to British domestic and foreign policy, and to activities of the Conservative Party.
Fraser of Kilmorack, Richard Michael Fraser, Baron, 1915-1996
Access
Microfilm use only.
Acquisition Information
Acquired in 1998.
Alternative Form Available
Also available on microfilm (117 reels).
Accruals
Increments may have been received since this finding aid was prepared. Please check Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/ to find the full extent of the collection.
Biographical Note
1915 Born, Nottingham, England, as Richard Michael Fraser (and using the name Michael Fraser as an adult)
1939-1946 Serves in the Royal Artillery, attaining rank of Lieutenant-Colonel
1946 Receives M.B.E. (Member of British Empire) award
1946-1964 Works in the Conservative Research Department, serving as Director from 1959 to 1964
1964-1975 Serves as Deputy Chair of the Conservative Party
1974 Awarded life peerage, becoming Baron Fraser of Kilmorack
1996 Died
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Baron Fraser of Kilmorack in the Hoover Institution Archives document a career spent in the higher echelons of the British Conservative Party during the three decades following World War II. In his work as a party official, including a term as Deputy Chair, Fraser participated in nearly every aspect of Conservative politics, including the devising of campaign strategies, the selection of party leaders, the management of public relations, and the choice of day-to-day tactics in parliamentary debate. The Fraser papers provide a view of the internal and external workings of the Conservative Party both in opposition and in government during a period of considerable change in British politics.
A detailed record of Conservative Party life is contained in the Letterbooks series of the papers, which consists largely of correspondence sent by Fraser to various party officials and politicians over a 30-year period. Much of this is concerned with administrative matters, but larger issues of power and policy are also addressed, as is the question of influencing British public opinion. The Alphabetical Correspondence series contains additional letters sent to and received from party leaders, including R. A. Butler, as well as correspondence with the Conservative prime ministers of the period, Anthony Eden, Harold Macmillan, Alec Douglas-Home, and, in particular, Edward Heath.
The Fraser papers include the minutes of proceedings of various Conservative Party bodies, both those taking place in the public arena, such as party conferences, and others involving private deliberations of the party leadership, such as the Leader's Consultative Committee and Steering Committee (see Conservative Party Meetings File). There is also material in this section relating to the evolution of British policy toward the European Community.
Among other activities, the work of the Conservative Research Department involved the sampling of public opinion as a guide to the formulation of party policy. Both poll results and political position papers can be found in the Conservative Research Department Administrative File of the Fraser papers. There is additional material concerning Conservative electoral strategies in the Subject File, which also contains documents assessing the domestic impact of the British role in the Suez crisis of 1956. As a whole, the Fraser papers represent a significant record of Conservative politics in the time between the Churchill era and the realignment of the party under the leadership of Margaret Thatcher.
Conservative Party (Great Britain); Conservatism.; Great Britain--Foreign relations--1945-; Great Britain--Politics and government--1945-1964.; Great Britain--Politics and government--1964-1979.; Great Britain.
- Microfilm Reel Content Guide
  Downloadable PDF file of the Microfilm Reel Content Guide
- Military Records,., 1942-1946 (Box 1-2)
  Scope and Contents note
  Correspondence, diagrams, indexes, memoranda, and reports, arranged by military posting and therein chronologically
  Correspondence, diagrams, indexes, memoranda, and reports
  - Instructor in Gunnery Duty Officer papers, 1st Anti-Aircraft Group
    - 1942 June 30-1943 July 5 (Folder 1: 1)
    - 1943 July 6-November 28 (Folder 1: 2)
    - 1943 November 28-1944 April 15 (Folder 1: 3)
    - 1944 April-July (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - Air Intelligence Duty Officer papers, 1945 April-1946 April (Folder 2: 2)
- Letterbooks,., 1946-1975 (Box 2-63)
  Correspondence, mainly outgoing, arranged chronologically. Includes accompanying memoranda, minutes, and reports
  - 1946 October-1947 May (Folder 2: 3)
  - 1947 June-December (Folder 2: 4)
  - 1948
    - January-March (Folder 2: 5)
    - April-June (Box-folder 3: 1)
    - July-October (Folder 3: 2)
    - November-December (Folder 3: 3)
  - 1949 (Box 4)
    - January-March (Folder 4: 1)
    - April-June (Folder 4: 2)
    - July-September (Folder 4: 3)
    - October-December (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - 1950
    - January-February (Folder 5: 2)
    - March-May (Folder 5: 3)
    - June-July (Folder 5: 4)
    - August-September (Box-folder 6: 1)
    - October (Folder 6: 2)
    - November (Folder 6: 3)
    - December (Folder 6: 4)
  - 1951
    - January (Folder 6: 5)
    - February (Folder 6: 6)
    - March-April (Box-folder 7: 1)
    - May-June (Folder 7: 2)
    - July-August (Folder 7: 3)
    - September-October (Folder 7: 4)
    - November-December (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - 1952
    - January-February (Folder 8: 2)
    - March-April (Folder 8: 3)
    - May-June (Folder 8: 4)
    - July-August (Folder 8: 5)
    - September-October (Box-folder 9: 1)
    - November-December (Folder 9: 2)
  - 1953
    - January-February (Folder 9: 3)
    - March-April (Folder 9: 4)
    - May-June (Folder 9: 5)
    - July-September (Folder 9: 6)
    - October-December (Box-folder 10: 1)
  - 1954
    - January-March (Folder 10: 2)
    - April-June (Folder 10: 3)
    - July-September (Folder 10: 4)
    - October-December (Box-folder 11: 1)
  - 1955
    - January-February (Folder 11: 2)
    - March (Folder 11: 3)
    - April (Folder 11: 4)
    - May (Folder 11: 5)
    - June-July (Box-folder 12: 1)
    - August-October (Folder 12: 2)
    - November-December (Folder 12: 3)
  - 1956
    - January (Folder 12: 4)
    - February (Folder 12: 5)
    - March (Folder 12: 6)
    - April (Box-folder 13: 1)
    - May (Folder 13: 2)
    - June (Folder 13: 3)
    - July-August (Folder 13: 4)
    - September (Folder 13: 5)
    - October (Box-folder 14: 1)
    - November (Folder 14: 2)
    - December (Folder 14: 3)
  - 1957
    - January (Folder 14: 4)
    - February (Folder 14: 5)
    - March (Box-folder 15: 1)
    - April (Folder 15: 2)
    - May (Folder 15: 3)
    - June (Folder 15: 4)
    - July (Folder 15: 5)
    - August (Folder 15: 6)
    - September (Folder 16: 1)
    - October (Folder 16: 2)
    - November (Folder 16: 3)
    - December (Folder 16: 4)
  - 1958
    - January (Folder 16: 5)
    - February (Folder 16: 6)
    - March (Box-folder 17: 1)
    - April (Folder 17: 2)
    - May (Folder 17: 3)
    - June (Folder 17: 4)
    - July (Folder 17: 5)
    - August (Box-folder 18: 1)
    - September (Folder 18: 2)
    - October (Folder 18: 3)
    - November (Folder 18: 4)
    - December (Folder 18: 5)
  - 1959 (Box 19)
    - January (Folder 19: 1)
    - February (Folder 19: 2)
    - March (Folder 19: 3)
    - April (Folder 19: 4)
    - May (Box-folder 20: 1)
    - June (Folder 20: 2)
    - July (Folder 20: 3)
    - August (Folder 20: 4)
    - September (Folder 20: 5)
    - October (Box-folder 21: 1)
    - November (Folder 21: 2)
    - December (Folder 21: 3)
  - 1960
    - January (Folder 21: 4)
    - February (Folder 21: 5)
    - March (Box-folder 22: 1)
    - April (Folder 22: 2)
    - May (Folder 22: 3)
    - June (Folder 22: 4)
    - July (Folder 22: 5)
    - August (Box-folder 23: 1)
    - September (Folder 23: 2)
    - October (Folder 23: 3)
    - November (Folder 23: 4)
    - December (Folder 23: 5)
  - 1961
    - January (Folder 23: 6)
    - February (Folder 24: 1)
    - March (Folder 24: 2)
    - April (Folder 24: 3)
    - May (Folder 24: 4)
    - June (Folder 24: 5)
    - July (Box-folder 25: 1)
    - August (Folder 25: 2)
    - September (Folder 25: 3)
    - October (Folder 25: 4)
    - November (Folder 25: 5)
    - December (Box-folder 26: 1)
  - 1962
    - January (Folder 26: 2)
    - February (Folder 26: 3)
    - March (Folder 26: 4)
    - April (Folder 26: 5)
    - May (Box-folder 27: 1)
    - June (Folder 27: 2)
    - July (Folder 27: 3)
    - August (Folder 27: 4)
    - September (Folder 27: 5)
    - October (Box-folder 28: 1)
    - November (Folder 28: 2)
    - December (Folder 28: 3)
  - 1963
    - January (Folder 28: 4)
    - February (Folder 28: 5)
    - March (Box-folder 29: 1)
    - April (Folder 29: 2)
    - May (Folder 29: 3)
    - June (Folder 29: 4)
    - July (Folder 29: 5)
    - August (Box-folder 30: 1)
    - September (Folder 30: 2)
    - October (Folder 30: 3)
    - November (Folder 30: 4)
    - December (Folder 30: 5)
  - 1964 (Box 31)
    - January (Folder 31: 1)
    - February (Folder 31: 2)
    - March (Folder 31: 3)
    - April (Folder 31: 4)
    - May (Box-folder 32: 1)
    - June (Folder 32: 2)
    - July (Folder 32: 3)
    - August (Folder 32: 4)
    - September (Folder 32: 5)
    - October (Folder 33: 1)
    - November (Folder 33: 2)
    - December (Folder 33: 3)
  - 1965
    - January (Folder 33: 4)
    - February (Folder 33: 5)
    - March (Box-folder 34: 1)
    - April (Folder 34: 2)
    - May (Folder 34: 3)
    - June (Folder 34: 4)
    - July (Box-folder 35: 1)
    - August (Folder 35: 2)
    - September (Folder 35: 3)
    - October (Folder 35: 4)
    - November (Folder 35: 5)
    - December (Box-folder 36: 1)
  - 1966
    - January (Folder 36: 2)
    - February (Folder 36: 3)
    - March (Folder 36: 4)
    - April (Folder 36: 5)
    - May (Box-folder 37: 1)
    - June (Folder 37: 2)
    - July (Folder 37: 3)
    - August (Folder 37: 4)
    - September (Folder 37: 5)
    - October (Box-folder 38: 1)
    - November (Folder 38: 2)
    - December (Folder 38: 3)
  - 1967
    - January (Folder 38: 4)
    - February (Folder 38: 5)
    - March (Box-folder 39: 1)
    - April (Folder 39: 2)
    - May (Folder 39: 3)
    - June (Folder 39: 4)
    - July (Folder 39: 5)
    - August (Box-folder 40: 1)
    - September (Folder 40: 2)
    - October (Folder 40: 3)
    - November (Folder 40: 4)
    - December (Folder 40: 5)
  - 1968 (Box 41)
    - January (Folder 41: 1)
    - February (Folder 41: 2)
    - March (Folder 41: 3)
    - April (Folder 42: 1)
    - May (Folder 42: 2)
    - June (Folder 42: 3)
    - July (Folder 42: 4)
    - August (Box-folder 43: 1)
    - September (Folder 43: 2)
    - October (Folder 43: 3)
    - November (Box-folder 44: 1)
    - December (Folder 44: 2)
  - 1969
    - January (Folder 44: 3)
    - February (Box-folder 45: 1)
    - March (Folder 45: 2)
    - April (Folder 45: 3)
    - May (Folder 45: 4)
    - June (Box-folder 46: 1)
    - July (Folder 46: 2)
    - August (Folder 46: 3)
    - September (Box-folder 47: 1)
    - October (Folder 47: 2)
    - November (Folder 47: 3)
    - December (Box-folder 48: 1)
  - 1970
    - January (Folder 48: 2)
    - February (Folder 48: 3)
    - March (Box-folder 49: 1)
    - April (Folder 49: 2)
    - May (Folder 49: 3)
    - June (Box-folder 50: 1)
    - July (Folder 50: 2)
    - August (Folder 50: 3)
    - September (Folder 50: 4)
    - October (Box-folder 51: 1)
    - November (Folder 51: 2)
    - December (Folder 51: 3)
  - 1971
    - January (Folder 51: 4)
  - February (Box-folder 52: 1)
    - March (Folder 52: 2)
    - April (Folder 52: 3)
    - May (Folder 52: 4)
    - June (Box-folder 53: 1)
    - July (Folder 53: 2)
    - August (Folder 53: 3)
    - September (Folder 53: 4)
    - October (Folder 54: 1)
    - November (Folder 54: 2)
    - December (Folder 54: 3)
  - 1972
    - January (Folder 54: 4)
    - February (Box-folder 55: 1)
    - March (Folder 55: 2)
    - April (Folder 55: 3)
    - May (Folder 55: 4)
    - June (Box-folder 56: 1)
    - July (Folder 56: 2)
    - August (Folder 56: 3)
    - September (Folder 56: 4)
    - October (Box-folder 57: 1)
    - November (Folder 57: 2)
    - December (Folder 57: 3)
  - 1973
    - January (Folder 57: 4)
    - February (Box-folder 58: 1)
    - March (Folder 58: 2)
    - April (Folder 58: 3)
    - May (Folder 58: 4)
    - June (Box-folder 59: 1)
    - July (Folder 59: 2)
    - August (Folder 59: 3)
    - September (Folder 59: 4)
    - October (Box-folder 60: 1)
    - November (Folder 60: 2)
    - December (Folder 60: 3)
  - 1974
    - January (Folder 60: 4)
    - February (Box-folder 61: 1)
    - March (Folder 61: 2)
    - April (Folder 61: 3)
    - May (Folder 61: 4)
    - June (Folder 61: 5)
    - July (Box-folder 62: 1)
    - August (Folder 62: 2)
    - September (Folder 62: 3)
    - October (Folder 62: 4)
    - November (Folder 62: 5)
    - December (Box-folder 63: 1)
  - 1975
    - January (Folder 63: 2)
    - February (Folder 63: 3)
    - March (Folder 63: 4)
    - April (Folder 63: 5)
- Personal Correspondence,., 1967-1971 (Box 64)
  Letters, memoranda, and enclosures, arranged chronologically
  - 1967 (Folder 64: 1)
  - 1968 (Folder 64: 2)
  - 1969
    - January-June (Folder 64: 3)
    - July-December (Folder 64: 4)
  - 1971 (Folder 64: 5)
- Alphabetical Correspondence,., 1951-1976 (Box 65, Box 65-74)
  Letters, memoranda, and enclosures, arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent
  - Amory, Derick Heathcoat, 1958-1960 (Folder 65: 1)
  - Beer, Samuel H., 1953-1964 (Folder 65: 2)
  - Bishop, F. A., 1959-1964 (Folder 65: 3)
  - Blakenham, Viscount, 1963-1967 (Folder 65: 4)
  - Buchanan-Smith, Alick, Sir, 1960-1962 (Folder 65: 5)
  - Butler, R. A.
    - 1951-1953 (Folder 65: 6)
    - 1954 (Folder 65: 7)
    - 1955 (Folder 65: 8)
    - 1956 (Box-folder 66: 1)
    - 1957 (Folder 66: 2)
    - 1958 (Folder 66: 3)
    - 1959 (Folder 66: 4)
    - 1960
      - January-June (Folder 66: 5)
      - July-December (Box-folder 67: 1)
    - 1961
      - January-June (Folder 67: 2)
      - July-December (Folder 67: 3)
    - 1962 (Folder 67: 4)
    - 1963 (Folder 67: 5)
    - 1964 (Folder 67: 6)
    - ., 1965-1972 (Box-folder 68: 1)
    - ., 1973-1976 (Folder 68: 2)
    - Miscellany. (Folder 68: 3)
  - Churchill, Winston, Sir, 1958-1964 (Folder 68: 4)
  - Curran, Charles, 1954-1968 (Folder 68: 5)
  - Deedes, William, 1962-1964 (Folder 68: 6)
  - Douglas-Home, Alec, Sir, 1963-1966 (Folder 68: 7)
  - Du Cann, Edward, 1965-1968 (Folder 68: 8)
  - Eden, Anthony, Sir, 1956-1964 (Box-folder 69: 1)
  - Egremont, John, Lord, 1965-1969 (Folder 69: 2)
  - Goldman, Peter,., 1968-1975 (Folder 69: 3)
  - Hailsham, Viscount
    - 1957 (Folder 69: 4)
    - 1958 (Folder 69: 5)
    - 1959-1963 (Folder 69: 6)
  - Heath, Edward
    - 1956-1960 (Folder 69: 7)
    - 1961-1965 (Folder 69: 8)
    - 1966 (Box 70)
      - January-June (Folder 70: 1)
      - July-December (Folder 70: 2)
    - 1967
      - January-June (Folder 70: 3)
      - July-August (Folder 70: 4)
    - 1968 (Folder 70: 5)
    - 1969
      - January-June (Folder 70: 6)
      - July-August (Box-folder 71: 1)
    - 1970
      - January-June (Folder 71: 2)
      - July-December (Folder 71: 3)
    - 1971 (Folder 71: 4)
    - ., 1972 (Folder 71: 5)
    - ., 1973 (Box-folder 72: 1)
    - ., 1974
      - January-February (Folder 72: 2)
      - March-December (Folder 72: 3)
    - ., 1975 (Folder 72: 4)
    - Miscellany. (Folder 72: 5)
  - Hill, Charles, 1957-1964 (Folder 72: 6)
  - Hutchinson, George, 1968-1970 (Folder 72: 7)
  - Lloyd, Geoffrey (Box 73)
    - 1955-1962 (Folder 73: 1)
    - 1963-1964 (Folder 73: 2)
  - Lloyd, Selwyn, 1960-1964 (Folder 73: 3)
  - Low, Toby, Sir
    - 1959-1960 (Folder 73: 4)
    - 1961-1964 (Folder 73: 5)
  - Macleod, Iain
    - 1959-1961 (Folder 73: 6)
    - 1962 (Folder 73: 7)
    - 1963-1964 (Folder 73: 8)
  - Macmillan, Harold,., 1967-1977 (Box-folder 74: 1)
  - Maudling, Reginald, 1963-1964 (Folder 74: 2)
  - Poole, Oliver, Lord
    - 1955-1958 (Folder 74: 3)
    - 1959-1964 (Folder 74: 4)
  - Powell, Enoch (Folder 74: 5)
  - Redmayne, Martin
    - 1959-1962 (Folder 74: 6)
    - 1963-1964 (Folder 74: 7)
  - Soames, Christopher, Sir (Commission of the European Communities),., 1971-1974 (Folder 74: 8)
  - Thorneycroft, Peter, 1957 (Folder 74: 9)
  - Woolton, Earl, 1953-1963 (Folder 74: 10)
- Conservative Party Meetings File,., 1950-1975 (Box 75-90)
  Correspondence, minutes of proceedings, papers, speeches, and other records of Conservative Party bodies, arranged alphabetically by name of party body or meeting, and therein chronologically
  - Advisory Committee on Policy
    - 1950-1954 (Folder 75: 1)
    - 1955-1960 (Folder 75: 2)
    - 1961-1964 (Folder 75: 3)
  - Chequers meeting of party leaders, 1963 April 28 (Folder 75: 4)
  - Committee on Europe (Europe Coordinating Group, Executive Committee of Britain in Europe).
    Includes 1975 Britain in Europe referendum campaign records
    - 1970-1971 (Folder 75: 5)
    - 1972 (Folder 75: 6)
    - 1974-1975 (Folder 75: 7)
    - 1975 (Box-folder 76: 1-3)
  - Leader's Consultative Committee
    - Minutes
      - 1964 (Folder 76: 4)
      - 1965 (Folder 76: 5-6)
      - 1966 (Box-folder 77: 1-2)
      - 1967 (Folder 77: 3-4)
      - 1968 (Folder 77: 5)
      - 1968 (Contd.) (Folder 78: 1)
      - 1969 (Folder 78: 2-3)
      - 1970 (Folder 78: 4)
      - 1974 (Folder 78: 5)
      - 1974 (Contd.) (Folder 79: 1)
      - 1975 (Folder 79: 2-3)
    - Papers (numbered series of memoranda and position papers), 1964-1974
      - 1-20 (Folder 79: 4)
      - 21-30 (Folder 79: 5)
      - 31-50 (Box-folder 80: 1)
      - 51-70 (Folder 80: 2)
      - 71-88 (Folder 80: 3)
      - 89-118 (Folder 80: 4)
      - 119-140 (Folder 80: 5)
      - 141-154 (Folder 81: 1)
      - 156-170 (Folder 81: 2)
      - 171-190 (Folder 81: 3)
      - 191-199 (Folder 81: 4)
      - 201-210 (Folder 81: 5)
      - 211-240 (Box-folder 82: 1)
      - 241-250 (Folder 82: 2)
      - 251-270 (Folder 82: 3)
      - 271-275 (Folder 82: 4)
      - 276-284 (Folder 82: 5)
      - 74/1-74/20 (Folder 82: 6)
      - 74/21-74/40 (Box-folder 83: 1)
      - 74/41-74/54 (Folder 83: 2)
  - Liaison Committee
    - 1965 (Folder 83: 3)
    - 1970-1973 (Folder 83: 4)
  - Official Group on Policy
    - 1967 (Folder 83: 5)
    - 1968 (Folder 83: 6)
    - 1968 (Contd.) (Folder 84: 1-3)
    - 1969 (Folder 84: 4-5)
    - 1970 (Folder 84: 6)
    - 1971 (Box-folder 85: 1)
    - 1972 (Folder 85: 2)
    - 1973 (Folder 85: 3-4)
    - 1974 (Folder 85: 5)
  - Party Chairman's meetings (Box 86)
    - 1966-1968 (Folder 86: 1)
    - 1969 (Folder 86: 2)
    - 1970-1972 (Folder 86: 3)
  - Party Conferences
    - 1966-1968 (Folder 86: 4)
    - 1969-1972 (Folder 86: 5)
  - Policy Advisory Group, 1964 (Folder 86: 6)
  - Shadow Cabinet, 1970 (Folder 86: 7)
  - Shadow Cabinet, (Contd.), 1970 (Folder 87: 1)
  - Steering Committee
    - 1957-1958 (Folder 87: 2)
    - 1963
      - January-June (Folder 87: 3)
      - July-December (Folder 87: 4)
    - 1964
      - January-March (Folder 87: 5)
      - April-June (Box-folder 88: 1)
      - July (Folder 88: 2)
      - September (Folder 88: 3)
    - 1971 (Folder 88: 4)
    - 1972 (Folder 88: 5)
    - 1973 (Folder 89: 1)
    - 1974
      - January (Folder 89: 2-3)
      - February (Folder 89: 4-5)
    - 1975 (Box-folder 90: 1-2)
  - Taxation Subcommittee, 1956 (Folder 90: 3)
  - Miscellaneous local party meetings
    - 1947-1951 (Folder 90: 4)
    - 1954-1962 (Folder 90: 5)
- Conservative Research Department Administrative File,., 1930-1974 (Box 90-92)
  Calendar, correspondence, memoranda, opinion poll summaries, papers, and reports, arranged within a departmental history file and by physical form and subject, and therein chronologically
  - Departmental history and organization file
    - Correspondence and memoranda, 1948-1959 (Folder 90: 6)
    - Reports,., 1949-1967 (Folder 90: 7-9)
      Typescripts
  - Opinion poll summaries,., 1965-1974 (Box-folder 91: 1)
  - Press advertisements (by Conservative Party),., 1957-1958 (Folder 91: 2)
    Printed copies
  - United States, Contacts in.
    Correspondence
    - 1952 (Folder 91: 3)
    - 1954-1964 (Folder 91: 4)
  - Policy position papers.
    - 1946 (Folder 91: 5)
    - 1952-1959 (Folder 91: 6)
    - 1960 (Box-folder 92: 1)
    - 1961 (Folder 92: 2-3)
    - 1962-1963 (Folder 92: 4)
    - 1964 (Folder 92: 5-6)
    - 1966-1974 (Folder 92: 7)
  - Strategic calendar,., 1971 (Folder 92: 8)
    Printed copy
  - Administrative memoranda and correspondence, 1930-1971 (Folder 92: 9)
- Conservative and Unionist Central Office File,., 1964-1972 (Box 93-94)
  Correspondence, memoranda, and report, arranged alphabetically by physical form, and therein by subject and date
  - Correspondence and memoranda organized by subject, 1964-1972
    - Press advertisements
      - 1965-1969 (Folder 93: 1)
      - 1970 (Folder 93: 2)
    - Radio and television broadcasts
      - 1964-1968 (Folder 93: 3)
      - 1969-1970 (Folder 93: 4)
      - 1971 (Folder 93: 5)
      - 1972 (Box-folder 94: 1)
  - Report,., 1970 (Folder 94: 2)
    Typescript
- Subject File,., 1950-1974 (Box 94-96)
  Correspondence, graph, memoranda, minutes, notes, and reports, arranged alphabetically by subject
  - Agricultural ownership (Folder 94: 3)
  - Commonwealth Parliamentary Association (Folder 94: 4)
  - Elections
    - 1964 (Folder 94: 5-7)
    - 1970 (Folder 94: 8)
    - 1974 (Folder 94: 9)
    - 1974 (Box-folder 95: 1-2)
  - Electoral reform (Folder 95: 3)
  - Environment (Folder 95: 4)
  - House of Lords reform (Folder 95: 5)
  - Industrial relations (Folder 95: 6)
  - Leadership selection procedure of Conservative Party
    - 1963-1964 (Folder 95: 7)
    - 1965-1966 (Folder 95: 8)
    - 1974-1975 (Box-folder 96: 1)
  - Suez crisis, 1956 (Folder 96: 2)
  - Taxation policy (Folder 96: 3)
- Clippings,., 1939-1975 (Box 96-97)
  Articles largely relating to the Conservative Party and British politics
  - 1939-1948 (Folder 96: 4)
  - 1950-1960 (Folder 96: 5)
  - 1961-1963 (Folder 96: 6)
  - 1964 (Folder 96: 7)
  - 1965-1966 (Box-folder 97: 1)
  - 1967-1970 (Folder 97: 2)
  - 1971-1975 (Folder 97: 3)